(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
(MOVIE PLAYING ON SCREEN)
MAN ON SCREEN: Watch out!
(PROJECTOR WHIRRING)
(DRUMMING ON TABLE)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
You... Um... Your light.
What? Oh! I'm such a moron!
How's the flick?
Ah, you know, Adam Sandler gets in a mess.
Wife gets pissed. Rinse and repeat.
Predictable. Formulaic.
- Fart jokes. You wouldn't like it.
- Hmm.
How would you know what I like?
(CLEARS THROAT)
(STAMMERING) I wouldn't know.
Well, maybe you should find out sometime.
(PROJECTOR WHIRRING)
(LAUGHING)
(WHIRRING STOPS)
Oh, shit! What the...
Hey, Hal! Hey...
What the hell?
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Hal?
What the... What the hell's going on?
(DOOR OPENING)
Kim?
(FOOTSTEPS RUNNING)
(BABY CRYING)
(PANTING)
GUARD: Hey! Hey! Hey, you.
Everyone's gone. They're all gone.
Got anyone in the theaters?
No, man. I haven't seen a soul.
GUARD: Jeez! Same down in the food court.
PAUL: You know what happened?
GUARD: We're on backup power.
Heading down to maintenance
to find out more.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
(NERVOUS CHUCKLE)
We're being Punk'd, right?
PAUL: Oh, yeah.
Allen Funt is gonna pop out any minute.
- GUARD: Who?
- Forget it.
The hell is that?
PAUL: What did you see?
Wait here.
GUARD: Who's there?
PAUL: You see something?
Huh?
(GUARD SCREAMS)
(RATTLING)
(CLANGING)
WOMAN: Anybody here?
Hello?
Anyone here?
(WOMAN PANTING)
Where is everyone?
Anybody here?
Hey! Hello?
(SNARLING)
(BEEPING)
(PATIENT MOANING)
(MUFFLED) Help me.
Someone help me.
(RAPID BEEPING)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
No!
Manny. Manny.
(SOBBING) My baby. Manny!
Paige?
I waited for you.
(YAWNS) You here?
Paige?
(FLICKING SWITCH)
(WATER DRIPPING)
(SIGHS)
Son of a...
What the hell is going on here?
Twenty-three goddamn flights.
(PANTING) Piece of junk.
Yo, Jesus, what's up with the...
- This is yesterday's.
- (CRUNCHING)
(BIRD CALLING)
(VOICES WHISPERING)
(PANTING) Paige?
Paige?
Anyone?
Where are you?
(EXCLAIMS)
Damn it!
(FAINT SQUEAKING)
Hello?
Somebody there?
(DOG BARKING)
(BIRD CAWING)
(FAINT WHISPERING)
(PANTING)
- (ENGINE SPUTTERS)
- LUKE: Shit!
(CLICKING)
(SIGHS)
- (BANGING)
- MAN: Hey!
Open the door!
(LOCK CLICKING)
Open up the fucking door, man!
Hey, man, I need... I need a light.
They're all spent.
Give me one of your lights, man.
Open the door.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
Give me one of your lights. Please.
God damn!
(MAN SCREAMS)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(ENGINE STARTING)
(VOICES WHISPERING)
(UPBEAT JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Hello, little boy
Don't you remember me?
Well, I'm the same one
that brought you from Tennessee
I said, "You came to the city
Got me in your heart"
Now don't forget that I'm the one
who put you wise
Please don't high jive me, baby
I ain't the jiving kind
No, don't high jive me, daddy
'Cause you'll find I'm hip
and you'll up and lose your mind
Down in Tennessee, you was ragged and beat
Walking around barefooted
drinking sneaky Pete
Don't get me started
I know just what to do
If you make me mad
I'll tell the whole world about you
(JAZZ MUSIC CONTINUES)
(RECORD SKIPS)
(RECORD CONTINUES PLAYING)
(DISTANT TAPPING)
(GENERATOR HUMMING)
(GENERATOR REVVING LOUDLY)
BOY: Don't move.
Put the gun on the floor.
It's a flashlight.
BOY: Just put it on the floor.
LUKE: You mean this gun?
Put or drop?
Put the fucking gun on the ground!
Come on, the light, too.
(SCOFFS) You want me to turn it off?
The light, too! Now!
LUKE: All right.
Okay. What now?
(SLOW JAZZ SONG PLAYING)
Why don't you just lower that barrel a little,
we'll talk this shit out, huh?
Can I at least have my drink?
Is that permitted?
(SCOFFING)
- (GUN FIRES)
- (LUKE EXCLAIMS)
Hey! God damn it!
Go on! Shoot me! Do it!
Shoot me!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You're afraid to.
- No, I'm not.
- Yeah, you are.
You shoot me, there's nobody left. Right?
(PANTING)
Right.
What's your name?
James.
James. Like Jesse James.
Gun and all.
I'm Luke.
I've seen your face.
Oh, yeah?
TV.
That's right.
News 7. I'm the new field reporter.
You're always yelling at people
with the microphone.
Look, James. Here's the truth.
I'm just happy to see another face.
You know what I mean?
Why don't you put the gun down
and we'll have ourselves a drink.
Come on, I'm buying.
It'll be my pleasure.
LUKE: Where'd you find this?
JAMES: It's my mom's.
She keeps it under the bar.
- LUKE: Your mom owns this place?
- Nah. Bartender.
LUKE: She around?
Up the street.
Went to check the light in the church.
- Light?
- Yeah.
A guy came by
saying he saw a light in that church.
A guy? How long ago?
He's gone now.
(SIGHS) You got a nice generator down there.
How much gas you got left?
I don't know.
My mom told me to keep feeding it
every few hours, though.
You a strong kid, Jesse James?
Strong enough.
Good. Drink up.
You're gonna need it.
Why?
Here. Batteries work.
You're gonna help us get us both out of here.
I'm not going nowhere.
I've got to wait for my mom.
She just went up the street to the church.
She told me to stay right here.
We need to get out of this city.
You understand?
I'm not going nowhere.
- (SIGHS)
- We're moving out
when she comes back with some people.
What people? There are no people.
Don't matter. She told me she'd be back.
Have you taken a look outside lately, James?
It's, like, 11:00 in the morning.
And it's fucking pitch black!
I've been out there for the last three days.
And every day the sun comes up later
and goes down sooner.
Every day, less daylight.
More people are just gone!
You understand what I'm saying?
I don't think your mom's coming back.
- Yes, she is!
- No, she's not.
Now, I don't know
what in Christ is going on here,
but I'm not hanging around
in this dump to find out.
You wanna just wait
till the gas is up in that genny,
knock yourself out. I'm out of here.
Fair exchange. Good luck.
I'm serious, all right? I'm going.
- I'm gone.
- Then go, motherfucker, go!
Where is he?
Manny, baby, it's Mama. Manny!
What'd he do with my Manny?
Come on.
Hey, lady.
- Please, you've seen my Manny?
- I don't know. I don't know.
- My baby.
- I don't know, I don't know.
Randy, where you at?
Hey, lady, there's nobody else here, all right?
Randy! Randy!
He took my baby.
I know he took my baby.
(SOBBING)
Look, I'm real sorry for your...
- Get away from my baby!
- Whoa, whoa! Hey!
- Where's my baby?
- Don't you point that gun at me!
- God damn it!
(GUN FIRING)
(WEEPING)
(SOBBING) Help me. Help me.
(SQUEALING)
(GASPS)
(SLOW JAZZ SONG PLAYING)
So, how'd you get this far without a light?
You didn't have one when you came in here.
How old are you?
Twelve-and-a-half.
Manny's nine months today.
JAMES: That's your boy?
Yeah.
I'm James.
That's Luke.
Rosemary.
You a doctor?
WOMAN ON PA:
Dr. Williamson, please report to the ER.
(BABY CRYING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(CARS CRASHING)
(BIRD CHIRPING)
Gloria? (EXCLAIMS)
Manny? Manny!
(IN BROKEN VOICE) Please... God...
(CRYING)
JAMES: You a doctor?
Physical therapist.
Manny's dad comes here to drink,
so I thought that...
I thought that he took our baby here.
I...
JAMES: It's okay.
You're okay.
I do have light.
I got a lot of lights.
The batteries kept dying in my flashlight.
These last.
Why does the power work here?
LUKE: Backup generator.
Won't last, though.
You're the first people I've seen in two days.
- Why?
- Why what?
Why us?
Why are we the ones left behind?
(MAN SCREAMING FAINTLY)
LUKE: Just stay close to the light.
Just stay in the light, all right?
MAN: Help! Help!
Help!
Someone help me!
Sounds like he's hurt.
Bad luck for him.
What? We can't just leave him.
MAN: Someone help me, please!
Go get him, then.
(MAN SCREAMING)
- I'll go.
- No. No.
- You stay here. I'll go.
- Give it to me. Move.
Lock the door.
Then open it when you hear me coming.
Fast!
ROSEMARY: Come on, let's get inside.
(MAN GROANING)
- Help me!
- Shh.
Help me! Help me!
LUKE: All right.
- Come on. You're coming with me.
- No! No!
- It's all right, it's okay.
Come on. (GRUNTING)
- PAUL: They're here. They're here.
- No, it's just me.
They're here.
Shit!
Come on! Not now.
They're here.
They're out there. They're here.
Here.
(VOICES MOANING)
All right, come on. One more time.
(SQUEALING)
(BOTH PANTING)
Mama.
What are you doing?
I got to find my ma.
I got to go. She's waiting for me!
We have to stay in the light. I'm sorry.
He ain't coming back, is he?
(LUKE PANTING)
LUKE: We're almost there.
(GROANING)
No!
(GROANING) Come on!
Hey!
Hey! Open the door!
Open the door!
Come on! The lights! Hurry up!
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
(SLOW JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
What, am I in heaven?
LUKE: Better.
A bar. (PANTING)
I gotta go. I gotta go.
- No, lie still. Just...
- I gotta go.
What's your name?
Can you tell me your name?
My name is Paul. Paul.
- Paul, that's my name.
- Good.
You have a concussion.
So we need to keep talking. Okay?
- Okay.
- Right.
That light.
How'd you get there?
I...
I was working at the Fairlane Center.
And the whole mall went dark.
I mean, all the people were all gone.
So, I was... I was on my way out of there,
when my light starts dying.
And then someone
came out of the dark and hit me.
I was taken somewhere.
And then my light came back on.
And I was outside.
I don't even know how I got there, but l...
I walked till I found that bus shelter.
Taken?
Taken.
I don't know where.
But there were these voices.
These whispers.
No bodies. No faces.
Souls.
Only shadows.
And I was drowning in them.
So I started screaming. Started screaming.
But there was no sound.
There was no sound.
It was like I was fighting, fighting for air.
Like I was fighting to exist.
Sounds like some kind of fever dream.
No. Dreams are much more broken apart,
more obscure.
- I was taken some place for three days.
- ROSEMARY: I'm gonna keep you warm.
This was in real time.
LUKE: So, did you get a look
at the guy that hit you?
I told you. I told you it wasn't a person.
You saw it, too, didn't you?
I knew it.
When I was lying there, waiting for the bus,
I had time and I went through the list
of all the ways everyone could just disappear.
Flesh eating bacterias.
Nanotech running amok.
A particle collider accident.
Parallel universes.
Neutron bombs. Gamma ray bursts.
Alien abduction.
Singularities. Wormholes. Black holes.
- Stop it!
- But the thing is
that the math doesn't add up.
The math does not add up.
My boy is missing.
His mother.
PAUL: It just doesn't add up.
This is no accident. There's a reason.
You're gonna lay
your Catholic guilt on us now?
Why are you here, Luke?
You know?
No idea. And I don't care.
Well, you should.
We all... We all should.
Why didn't we go with everyone else?
- PAUL: Because...
- Why?
Like, when you shut down a movie projector,
it doesn't just stop on a dime. It winds down.
We're the last spin on the reel
before it stops for good.
I know I've done things in my life.
- (SIGHING)
- Awful things.
I've hurt people.
I've made mistakes.
We all have.
(STAMMERING) So what are you saying,
that this is punishment?
For what?
- That's between you and...
- And God?
Between me and God?
I don't know, I think God's closed up shop,
just like everybody else!
Don't say that!
You're trying to tell me
- that he deserves this shit, huh?
- Leave him alone!
You know, I think that you're just pissed off
- 'cause Jesus didn't beam you up!
- Stop it! No!
You know what? We don't need
some fucking left behind sermon!
What we need to do is...
Oh, no!
(SQUEALING)
Sweet Jesus. Sweet Jesus.
(RECORD SKIPPING)
Lessen the load.
- What?
- The power load on the genny!
- You got to lessen it.
- LUKE: Turn off anything we don't need.
James, get the games.
The jukebox.
Turn them off, turn them off.
Get the neon signs.
(GENERATOR RUNNING)
PAUL: Strip the top off.
Looks like somebody rerouted it up to the bar
after the main grid died.
JAMES: Yeah. My ma.
At least we got plenty of gas.
It doesn't matter. It doesn't matter.
The electric charge is fading, anyway.
- Like the batteries and the flares...
- And the cars and everything.
It's just impossible.
But the bus shelter? The one you were under?
LUKE: Solar powered.
It's experimental, one off.
The city was thinking of going green
for a while. I did a piece on it.
Okay. So, solar is working.
Yeah. Too bad the sun's not.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
James, where does this go?
Sonny says it's where we go
when the shit hits the fan.
Sonny had a point.
All right, rocket scientist. How long?
- How long what?
- How long we got?
- How long until it dies?
- ALL: Yeah.
PAUL: Couple hours, I don't know.
Couple minutes, I don't know.
I don't know. There are no known laws
of physics operating here, okay?
I don't fucking know. I don't know!
(ALL SHOUTING)
ROSEMARY: Please, God.
Please, God. Please, God.
(SQUEALING)
(GROANS)
LUKE: Hey, come on, take it easy.
Okay, okay.
(PANTING)
ROSEMARY: Please, God. Please, God.
Please, God. Please, God. Help us.
There's this island.
This island right off the Carolinas,
called Roanoke.
And in 1587 it was... (CLEARING THROAT)
It was the first English colony.
117 men, women
and children were living there.
Then, one day a boat
comes from London with supplies.
But lo and behold, there's nobody to supply,
'cause everybody's gone.
The whole entire colony completely vanished.
Left everything behind.
Food, livestock, clothing.
They sent search parties
looking for everybody for days
and the only thing they find...
You know what they find? One word.
One word.
Just scratched... Scratched on a fence post.
(ENUNCIATING) Croatoan.
JAMES: Cro... What?
Croatoan.
What does it mean?
I don't know. Nobody knows.
It's just a big mystery.
Maybe it's a message
from the local Indians or...
Or a word or...
Or just a last word.
Nobody knows for sure.
But maybe it's...
Maybe it's a warning.
A warning, like an error warning
your computer gives you
right before it crashes.
A warning from who?
Does it really matter? Huh?
Someone just hit
the restart button and...
And the lost colony was just
this little warning right before the...
Right before (STAMMERS) this big reboot.
- Whoa!
(GROANING) Feels like a semi
smashed into my skull.
That's 'cause you think too much.
James, wet the towel, sweetie.
There we go.
We need ice.
(GRUNTING)
I'm just gonna raise your head up.
Just breathe. Breathe. Breathe.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
LUKE: Hello?
Anybody here?
Stephen?
Is somebody here?
(SQUEALING)
Control.
(TAPE SQUEAKING)
STEPHEN:...news.
Reporter Luke Ryder continues
his series on the storm of controversy
surrounding alleged security lapses
at the West Haven nuclear power plant.
Yeah, you definitely don't want to miss that.
And speaking of storms, Paige.
(LAUGHS) Well, that's right,
Carolin and Stephen,
we're tracking a very large front
moving in our direction.
Kind of an unusual storm...
(TAPE SQUEAKING)
... the good news is this low pressure system
is followed by a very nice
high pressure front, so things...
(PAIGE SCREAMING)
(TAPE SQUEAKING)
PAIGE: So things... (SCREAMING)
DAVID:...defies any logical or
rational explanation.
LUKE: Hey. Hey!
DAVID: You can't say that it's evil.
You can't say that it's human
or not human.
But it is
the new law of nature.
And we have to adapt.
Last night after the blackout,
I heard my brother call out to me
from the darkness.
My brother died eight years ago
in an automobile accident.
It can trick you.
Stay near a light source.
But do not trust any light other than the one
that you hold in your own hand.
This is David Breadan, at WDID in Chicago.
If you're receiving this broadcast,
then your phone service may still work.
Please, call or text me at this number.
3-1-2-5-5-5-8-3-9...
LUKE: Damn it.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- Hello?
- WOMAN'S VOICE: Luke?
(VOICES WHISPERING)
(PANTING)
- (PAUL GROANING)
- All right.
We need to get out of here.
Now.
He can't go anywhere.
Don't you get it?
Why we're here?
At this exact place?
All of us?
I'll tell you why.
The light.
The light's protecting us.
LUKE: Protecting us?
Ever see moths fly into a flame?
What are you trying to say?
You trying to say that this is a trap?
LUKE: A trap!
A dead end.
But whatever's out there is in here now.
Point is when that genny dies, we die.
Maybe that's how it should be.
What?
ROSEMARY: All of us have seen it.
Those souls.
Out there in the dark.
How do we know they're not the people
we've already lost calling us over?
How do we know that that's not heaven
and this...
Is...
(VOICES WHISPERING)
If my boy's with them,
then that's where I'm meant to be.
And if he's not,
then I ain't going nowhere till I find him.
(GROANING)
Look, there's a truck.
I don't know, maybe five, eight blocks away.
The power's drained, but it's not dead.
Now if we can get it started,
we all have a chance of getting out of here.
Maybe get you to a hospital.
Oh, yeah? A hospital. Where, man?
Where?
Chicago.
The morning after it happened,
I caught a satellite feed.
There are survivors out there. Like us.
PAUL: So where are the rescue parties, huh?
I don't know.
It's been three days,
I don't see any search parties.
I don't know, all right?
All I know is I'm gonna
roll that truck to this genny.
I'm gonna string some jumper cables
from the genny to the truck's battery,
I'm gonna start that truck
and I'm gonna get out of here,
with or without any of you.
Yeah, roll? How you gonna roll it?
You can barely walk.
Then a little help would be nice.
James, we have a vehicle.
All right? We can cover more ground.
You know, maybe look for your mom.
Your son.
We can wait till morning.
You sure there's one coming?
The first couple of days, l...
You know, l...
Kept asking myself why am I still here.
Why me?
You know, just... Just... Just...
Talking to myself,
running from place to place,
shouting my name like an idiot.
Anything to remind me that I exist.
I'm here
because I will myself to exist.
You know what? Maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe this is just a passing storm.
Maybe it ends tomorrow.
You said it yourself, Paul.
A big reboot.
Which means that this could all be
a new beginning, right? Not an end.
But we can't wait around here to find out.
Those rations downstairs.
Put as many as you can
into these garbage bags, all right?
We need to bring them with us.
And keep an eye on that generator.
It goes black,
you take this and get out of here.
But what about Paul?
I'm supposed to watch him.
Hey, you heard what I said.
Here.
Take this, all right?
It's good luck.
I'll bring us back a real one.
PAUL: God, you're beautiful.
Let me tell you something.
You were born for the movies.
I think you missed your calling.
Yeah. King of missed opportunities.
That's me.
But I never missed a reel change.
Never.
Okay, once.
Tell me. Tell me as a woman,
as a beautiful woman. What do you think?
You think I might have a chance?
I mean, hypothetically.
Not with you, but just in general.
Do you think I'm...
You know, you think I'm...
I'm so fucking stupid.
Going on and on and on.
LUKE: Hey, we gotta go.
No. Hey, come back.
We will.
Don't let him fall asleep, okay?
Be brave.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(VOICES WHISPERING)
(LUKE GRUNTING)
ROSEMARY: Come on.
It's dead.
I just put batteries in four minutes ago.
LUKE: This'll do it.
It's right over here. Come on.
I must've checked 500 cars
since this happened.
Goddamn if this isn't the only one
with a battery that still works.
Why does this one work
and all the others don't?
It's a Chevy.
(GRUNTING)
There is no reason. All right?
It's random, you know.
Toss of a coin.
Why I'm still here and the sucker
who was driving this boat isn't,
I don't know. I had light, he didn't?
Just tell me what I have to do.
LUKE: Push!
Keep pushing.
You're fine.
You got a girl?
A what?
"A what?" Not a what, a girl.
A main squeeze.
I got a ma.
You got a ma.
Of course you got a ma, everybody's got a ma.
We all got a ma, but...
The Umbrellas of Cherbourg!
That's the movie
that I'm gonna screen for her.
1964.
Catherine Deneuve.
The music, the colors...
She's gonna love it.
Paul.
Paul. Paul!
Paul! Wake up!
Put on... Put on a song.
- A what?
- Go put a song on for me.
- But Luke says...
- I don't care what Luke says.
Just go, give me one more song. Go ahead.
See if they got Forever by the Marvelettes.
They got it.
Play it.
(FOREVER PLAYING)
(RECORD SKIPPING)
(SINGING) Darling, forever
Forever
You can break my heart
I'll play the part of a fool
Just to be with you
Forever
Darling, forever
You can torment me
Take my love for granted
But I'll always be just a fool
If I
If I could be with you
I'll be your slave
For the rest of
Of my days
Love you more in so
So many ways
Just to be with you
Thrills me through and through
And darling, forever
Forever
PAUL: James! James!
James! James!
James!
Paul! Come on, come on.
Wake up.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
LUKE: Hold up! Hold up!
ROSEMARY: It's just a few more blocks.
LUKE: No, I've got to stop for a second.
(GROANING)
My ankle. I just need a minute.
(RECORD SKIPPING)
PAUL: Hey, James.
James.
(MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
(MUSIC RESUMES PLAYING)
James!
They're all dead.
Your son. Does he talk yet?
Manny, right?
Does he talk?
He kind of makes funny sounds.
He can nearly say mama.
And sometimes he'll...
He'll point at a light and he says, "Lye!
"Lye, Mama."
It's almost "light," but not really.
What's in Chicago?
Anna. My wife.
We're separated actually.
I left for my career and she stayed for hers.
She's still there, Luke.
Funny thing is,
I don't think she'd want to see me.
Even now.
You'll be together again.
You will.
I just... I just put fresh batteries in.
Just keep dying.
Oh, my God. Look!
Hey!
Come here.
- Hey, there.
- ROSEMARY: It's okay.
- Come here.
- LUKE: Come here, it's all right.
It's all right, don't be afraid. Come here.
Come on.
Shit!
No! Come back!
(YELLING)
Luke!
Luke, get up!
(VOICES SQUEALING)
LUKE: Hit the lights!
Hit the headlights!
Come on, hit the lights!
ROSEMARY: Get out of there!
PAUL: James.
Oh, no.
James!
(SLOW SONG PLAYING)
ROSEMARY: None of them work.
None of them work.
This is the only one that works.
LUKE: Shit. Come on!
No, it doesn't work.
What are we gonna do?
Luke, they're here.
(WHISPERING) Come on.
Where are you going?
They're dimming.
(GENERATOR HUMMING)
James.
(CREAKING)
(GRUNTING)
That's better.
Hold this steady.
- All right.
- All right. That's good. That's good.
Give me your lighter.
Come on! Come on! Give me your lighter.
- It's in the bar.
- What?
It's in the bar!
(LUKE YELLS)
Where are you going?
Rosemary.
Whoa!
Hey, what are you doing?
ROSEMARY: Stay close.
- LUKE: There's not enough light.
- Come on!
ROSEMARY: We can make it.
We can make it.
It's really close.
PAUL: James.
ROSEMARY: Almost there!
This is it!
James!
James. Come...
Here.
JAMES: Paul.
(GRUNTING)
(ROSEMARY SCREAMS)
PAUL: James.
No! No!
No!
(VOICES MURMURING)
Who's there?
Stay away!
Stay away from me!
(YELLING)
No!
I exist.
I exist. I exist. I exist. I exist.
James.
I exist.
I exist!
James, I exist!
I exist...
(RECORD STARTS PLAYING)
(PANTING)
Paul.
Paul!
(JAZZ SONG PLAYING)
(VOICES WHISPERING)
Hold this.
How'd you know those matches were there?
I used to bum cigarettes off the duty nurse.
You worked here?
No.
Manny saved my life.
Made me want to clean up.
Made me want to live.
I can't lose him, Luke.
I can't.
This torch won't last.
We gotta go, Rosemary. Come on.
There's a storage room in the back.
There's alcohol.
For the needles.
Rubbing alcohol.
For the torch. Fuel, right?
Yeah. Yeah, let's go.
No, you rest your ankle.
You wait here. I'll go.
(RECORD SKIPPING)
(BABY WAILING)
Manny.
Rosemary?
My baby?
Manny.
No. No.
Almost there.
ROSEMARY: I exist.
I exist.
(GENERATOR SPUTTERING)
LUKE: James!
Hey!
Where's Paul?
He's gone. He's gone.
Rosemary?
Hey.
Hey, we're gonna make it.
All right?
Hey, we're gonna make it, all right?
But I need your help.
Okay?
Okay.
Come on, give me more slack.
There.
All right.
I gotta go down and prime that thing.
You're gonna have to turn the ignition
on your own, all right?
I can't be alone, man.
- Listen, you're not alone.
- No, don't go!
- You're gonna leave, too!
- No. It's you and me now, buddy.
- All right? Hey.
- Don't go, man. Don't go.
Listen to me.
Okay? We're gonna see morning, I promise.
JAMES: A storm passing.
- Right? Right?
- That's right.
That's right, a storm passing.
All right, when I say, "Now," turn the ignition.
Okay!
Now!
Come on.
Come on!
Now!
(SCREAMING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(VOICES SCREECHING)
Come on! Come on! Shit.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(BOTH PANTING)
I've gotta shut the hood.
You gotta keep your foot on the gas
otherwise we're gonna lose power. Yeah?
Yeah.
Don't take it off.
Okay. Okay.
You did good back there.
So did you.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Go!
(ENGINE REVVING)
Mama.
James, the gas! Hey!
James! Hey!
What are you doing? Hey!
Shit!
(ENGINE REVVING)
James!
James, get back here!
Shit. Shit. Shit.
Fuck it.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
WOMAN: (WHISPERING) James.
James.
Mom.
(WHISPERING) Mom. It's me.
(SCREECHING)
Get in the truck!
I saw my mom.
Get in the fucking truck.
James! No!
James!
James! James!
No!
Anna.
Luke!
My name is James Leary.
I exist.
I exist!
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
That's my bed.
You don't have to go.
Don't go.
I'm Briana.
I'm James.
It works?
It won't go out.
As long as there's day.
What's that?
Look!
VOICES: (MURMURING) I exist.
(YOUR GOOD THING
(IS ABOUT TO END) PLAYING)
(SINGING) I don't have to beg you to hold me
'Cause somebody else will
You don't have to love me when I want it
Your so-called friends say you don't need it
When all the time they're trying to get it
Look out
Your good thing
Is about to come to an end
Your real good thing
All those nights I watched the four walls
I did not have to watch them all alone
When other men said they wanted me
I didn't have to tell them
I was your very own
You have all the love I've got
Even ice melts to water and gets hot
Look out
Your good thing
Is about to come to an end
Your real good thing
Is about to end
Getting myself back together
Is gonna be a big problem, I know
But when the right man say he wants me
You can bet I won't say no
'Cause your real good thing
Is about to end
Your real, your good thing
Your good thing, baby
Your good thing
Is about to come to an end
Yeah, yeah
Yeah, your good thing
Your good thing